web graphics library is a javascript api for implementing
Web 图形库是一个 javascript api，用于
interactive 2d and 3d vector graphics in the browser
在浏览器中实现交互式 2d 和 3d 矢量图形，
it allows developers to run hardware accelerated graphics with the client's
它允许开发人员使用客户端的
gpu directly inside an html canvas without
gpu直接在 html 画布内运行硬件加速图形，而
the need for external plugins it opens the door to 3d web design
无需外部插件它打开了 3d 网页设计交互的大门
interactive games data vis physics simulations and most importantly
游戏数据与物理模拟，最重要的是
beautiful artwork webgl is used to render graphics in
精美的艺术品webgl 用于在
everyday tools like google maps and by the unity engine to make web-based games
谷歌地图等日常工具中渲染图形，并被统一引擎用于制作基于网络的游戏
to understand how it works it helps to first understand basic 3d theory
以了解其工作原理它有助于首先了解基本的 3d 理论
and the rendering pipeline in a 3d scene every point is a vertex
和渲染管道 在 3d 场景中，每个点都是
identified by its x y and z coordinates the vertices are then connected together
由其 x y 和 z 坐标标识的顶点，然后将顶点连接
to form a bunch of little triangles known as primitives
在一起形成一堆称为基元的小三角形，
then a light source bounces off of them to create the appearance of shadows and
然后光源从它们反射回来以产生阴影的外观和
depth perception they're then rasterized to convert
深度感知。  '然后被光栅化以
a 3d vector graphic into a projection of a 2d pixel
将 3d 矢量图形转换为 2d 像素的投影，
which tricks our brains into seeing a 3d object on a 2-dimensional computer
这会欺骗你在二维计算机屏幕上看到 3d 对象的大脑
screen this pipeline can be customized by
可以通过编写着色器来定制这条管道
writing shaders which are just functions that tell the computer how to draw
，这些着色器只是告诉计算机如何
pixels on the screen shading requires the computer to perform
在屏幕上绘制像素的函数着色需要计算机
a ton of linear algebra or matrix multiplication
执行大量线性代数或矩阵
to render graphics smoothly at 60fps it's often too much for the cpu to
以 60fps 平滑渲染图形的乘法通常对于 cpu 本身来说太多了，
handle by itself which is why we have gpus to distribute the calculations more
这就是为什么我们让gpus 更有效地分配计算
efficiently webgl allows us to process graphics on the gpu
webgl允许我们在 gpu 上处理图形，
and is based on a library that's been around since 1992 called opengl
并且基于自 1992 年以来一直存在的库 调用opengl
to get started you just need to grab an html canvas in the dom
开始你只需要在dom中获取一个html画布
then get its webgl contacts to start drawing the main program code is written
然后获取它的webgl联系人开始绘制主程序代码是用javascript编写的
in javascript but shaders are written in the opengl es
，但着色器是用opengl es
shading language a shader will take information about a
着色语言编写的着色器将获取有关
vertex or fragment and use the gpu to calculate the data required to render it
顶点的信息 或片段并使用 gpu计算将其渲染
as a pixel on the screen luckily you don't need to write shaders
为屏幕上的像素所需的数据，幸运的是您不需要通过 h 编写着色器
by hand to start adding 3d graphics to your website you can use libraries like
并开始将 3d 图形添加到您的网站，您可以使用
3js or tools like spline to quickly design 3d experiences without much
3js 之类的库或 spline 之类的工具来快速设计 3d 体验，而无需太多
underlying knowledge of webgl stay tuned for a full 3js tutorial make
webgl 基础知识 请继续关注完整的 3js 教程
sure to hit the like button thanks for watching and i will see you
确保点击赞按钮感谢观看，我会的
in the next one
下一篇见